[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
We now seen how to express the probability of y equals plus 1,
شاهدنا الآن كيفية توضيح احتمالية أن تساوي y القيمة +1،
the probability of y equals minus 1, and
واحتمالية أن تساوي y القيمة -1،
when I plug those into the log likelihood before we take its gradient.
وعندما أقوم بإدخال كلتا الاحتماليتين في احتمالات اللوغاريتم قبل أن نأخذ معامل التدرج.
There's still part of that very,
لا يزال هناك جزء من هذا
very optional derivation that we're doing of the gradient of logistic regression.
الاشتقاق الاختياري للغاية الذي نقوم به على معامل تدرج الانحدار اللوجستي.
Now we have probability y=+1, probability y=-1.
والآن لدينا الاحتمالية y=+1، والاحتمالية y=-1.
We can go ahead and plug those into our log likelihood function.
ويمكننا إدخال كلتا الاحتماليتين في دالة احتمالات اللوغاريتم لدينا.
And with the indicators and all that good stuff, let's see what happens.
ومع هذه المؤشرات وكل تلك الأشياء الجيدة، لذا دعونا نرى ما سيحدث.
So I'm going to go ahead and plug in this definition of probability y=+1,
سأقوم بإدخال هذا التعريف حول الاحتمالية y=+1،
y=-1 into log likelihood, It turns out the log likelihood is going to simplify
وy=-1 إلى احتمالات اللوغاريتم، ومن الواضح أن احتمالات اللوغاريتم ستقوم بتبسيط
to a pretty cool term and we're going to take the derivative of it, and
هذا التعريف إلى حد أبسط قليلًا، وسنأخذ مشتقة هذه الدالة
derive the derivative that we're hoping for.
ونحصل على المشتقة التي نريدها.
So here we go.
لذا، لنبدأ.
So I'm just going to first plug in the probability y=+1 into the first term.
وبالتالي، سأقوم أولًا بإدخال الاحتمالية y=+1 إلى الحد الأول.
So we're going to have that the log likelihood function is the indicator
ولذا، ستكون دالة احتمالات اللوغاريتم هي المؤشر أن
that y is i = + 1 so we're only going to deal with one data point for
yi=+1،
now and then we'll get the sum over the data points later.
وسنتعامل مع نقطة بيانات واحدة في الوقت الحالي ثم سنحصل على مجموع نقاط البيانات لاحقًا.
So of the log of that ratio so 1/1+e- w transpose,
لذا، بالنسبة لاحتمالات اللوغاريتم لهذه النسبة سيكون، 1 على 1+-e
h(xi), this is the particular data point we're dealing with.
(wt h(xi، وهذه هي نقطة البيانات المحددة التي نتعامل معها.
So that was easy, that was the first one.
كان الأمر سهلًا، وهذا هو الحد الأول.
Now for the second term here, we need to plug in the probability y=-1.
والآن، بالنسبة للحد الثاني، فنحن في حاجة إلى إدخال الاحتمالية y=-1.
But it's a little bit annoying for a derivation that we have an indicator that
ولكن الأمر مزعج بعض الشيء بالنسبة للاشتقاق، حيث سيكون لدينا مؤشر
yi is +1 and another indicator that yi is -1, so we're going to take this
على أن yi=+1 ومؤشر آخر على أن yi=-1، لذا سنأخذ هذا المؤشر
indicator that yi = -1 and substitute it with something else.
أن yi=-1 ونستبدله بشيء آخر.
So let's do a change of colors transformation here and
دعونا نقم بتغيير في تبديل الألوان هنا
just remind ourselves that the indicator that yi = -1,
ودعونا نذكر أنفسنا أن المؤشر yi = -1،
this takes value 1 when y=-1.
وهذا يأخذ القيمة 1 عندما تكون y = -1.
Can be written as 1 minus
ويمكن أن تكتب -1 ثم المؤشر أن
the indicator that yi=+1.
yi = +1.
So if you think about it,
لذا، إذا فكرت في الأمر.
when yi=-1,
عندما تكون yi = -1،
then the left side here is 1 and the right side is also 1.
فحينها يكون الجانب الأيسر هنا 1 والجانب الأيمن 1 أيضًا.
If yi = -1, the left side is 0 and the right side is 0.
إذا كانت yi = -1، فإن الجانب الأيسر يكون 0 والجانب الأيمن 0.
So let's plug that in, what we just learned.
لذا، دعونا نقم بإدخال ما تعلمناه للتو.
And so from the first term here,
وبالتالي، من الحد الأول هنا، نحصل على -1
we get 1 minus indicator that yi = -1.
ثم مؤشر على أن yi = -1.
And we're going to plug in the definition of the probability that y = -1.
وسنقوم بإدخال التعريف حول الاحتمالية أن y = -1.
So that's log of e to the -w transpose
وسيكون اللوغاريتم e أس (wt h(xi-
h(xi) / 1 + e to the 1 + e to
مقسومًا على +1
the -w transpose h(xi).
e أس (wt h(xi-.
Great, so now we have our two terms and now we're going to move a couple
رائع، والآن لدينا الحدين، والآن سنقوم
of things around and simplify the equations pretty significantly.
بتحريك اثنين من الأشياء لتبسيط المعادلات إلى حد كبير.
So let's go ahead and do that.
لذا، دعونا نقم بذلك.
Okay, let's go back to our change of colors transformation,
حسنًا، دعونا نعد إلى تغيير تبديل الألوان
with dealing with the first terms.
عند التعامل مع الحد الأول.
The first term is the red term, so let's go back to the red term.
والحد الأول هو الحد الملون بالأحمر، لذا دعونا نعود إلى الحد ذو اللون الأحمر.
And let's see what the log of 1 / 1
ولنرَ كيف يبدو اللوغاريتم 1 / 1
+ e to the -w transpose h(xi) looks like.
1 على 1+e أس (wt h(xi-.
And, the log of 1 over something turns out to be minus the log of something.
واللوغاريتم الذي يمثل 1 على شيء ما، يتضح أن يكون سالب لوغاريتم شيء ما.
And there's something here, is 1 + e to the -w, transpose h(xi).
وهذا الشيء هنا هو، 1+ e أس (wt h(xi-.
So plugging that in, we get the indicator
وبإدخال ذلك في المعادلة، نحصل على المؤشر
that yi = +1 that multiplies minus
أن yi = +1 مضروبًا في
the log of 1 + 8 to the -w transpose h.
سالب لوغاريتم 1+e أس (wt h(xi-.
So we're going to write here log of 1
لذا سنكتب هنا، لوغاريتم
+ e to the -w transpose h(xi),
1=e أس (wt h(xi-،
and put the minus sign out here.
ونضع علامة السالب بالخارج.
That was for the first term, so
وكان ذلك بالنسبة للحد الأول،
now let's look at that famous second term and expand it out.
لذا، لنتجه إلى الحد الثاني المعروف لدينا ونقوم بتوسيعه.
So let's go back to our blue.
وبالتالي سنعود إلى اللون الأزرق.
And so the coefficient here stayed the same.
وبالتالي يظل المعامل هنا بنفس القيمة.
The 1 minus the indicator that yi is positive,
1- المؤشر أن yi =
so yi is positive, sorry about that,
yi = +1، أسف لذلك،
of the log of that ratio.
للوغاريتم تلك النسبة.
So let's explore what the log of the ratio looks like.
لذا، دعونا نستكشف ما يبدو عليه لوغاريتم هذه النسبة.
So, the log of e to the -w
لوغاريتم e أس
transpose h(xi) / 1+e
(wt h(xi-، مقسومًا على
to the -w transpose h(xi).
1+e أس (wt h(xi-.
And so what does that look like?
وكيف يبدو ذلك؟
That looks like it's the log of the ratio so
ذلك يبدو كما لو أنه لوغاريتم هذه النسبة، لذا فالأمر متعلق باختلاف اللوغاريتم،
it's the difference of the log so
لذا، لوغاريتم e أس
it's the log of e to the power of -w transpose h(xi)
(wt h(xi-، ناقص لوغاريتم
minus the log of 1 + e to the power of -w transpose h(xi).
1+e أس (wt h(xi-.
Let's note two things, first the second term is exactly what we had up here,
ولنلاحظ اثنين من الأشياء، أول شيء هو أن الحد الثاني هو تمامًا مثل الذي لدينا بالأعلى هنا.
so things are starting to look very similar.
لذا، فقد بدأت الأمور أن تصبح متشابهة.
And what is the log of the first term?
وما هو لوغاريتم الحد الأول؟
And here's another log trick.
وهذه هي خدعة لوغاريتمية أخرى.
Log of e to the something, say e to the a is exactly equal to a.
لوغاريتم e أس شيء ما، ولنفترض e أس a، تساوي تمامًا a.
So in this case, the log of each of the -w
وبالتالي، في هذه الحالة، فإن لوغاريتم wt h-
transpose h is just -w transpose h(xi).
يساوي (wt h(xi-.
So plug in that n, we get a coefficient
وبإدخال ذلك هنا، نحصل على المعامل مضروبًا في
that multiplies -w transpose h(xi)
اللوغاريتم (wt h(xi-
minus the same term as the other side,
مطروحًا من نفس الحد الموجود بالجانب الآخر.
log of 1 + e to the -w transpose h(xi).
لوغاريتم 1+e أس (wt h(xi-.
Okay, going a little slowly, and now you can shake things around, move things,
حسنًا، وبالتمعن في ذلك، يمكنكم الآن تحريك بعض الأشياء،
lots of stuff cancels out, I'm not going to go through that in detail,
الكثير من الأشياء التي يتم إلغائها، لن أخوض في ذلك الأمر بالتفصيل،
but you're welcome to do it.
ولكن يمكنكم القيام بذلك.
I'm just going to do a change of color transformation,
سأقوم فقط بتغيير تبديل الألوان،
go to purple which is a color I love, and just write out what the answer is.
ثم أقوم باختيار اللون الأرجواني الذي أحبه، وأقوم بكتابة الإجابة فقط.
And the answer here becomes log likely can be written as for
والإجابة هنا يمكن أن تكون، احتمالية كتابة اللوغاريتم
[INAUDIBLE] point as 1 minus
لنقطة بيانات محددة كسالب 1-
the indicator that it is a positive example.
ثم المؤشر، ولأن ذلك مثال إيجابي،
So, yi =+1.
ستكون yi = +1.
That multiplies w transpose h(xi)
مضروبًا في (wt h(xi
minus the log of that crazy term 1+e
مطروحًا من لوغاريتم ذلك الحد الغريب
to the -w transpose h(xi).
1+e أس (wt h(xi-.
So, we started from the log likelihood function, we went through
لذا، فقد بدأنا بدالة احتمالات اللوغاريتم، ثم خوضنا خلال مجموعة من الاشتقاقات والرياضيات
a bunch of derivations and maths which you can explore if you want and
والذي يمكنك استكشافها إذا أردت،
we ended up with this much simpler form.
وانتهينا بهذا الشكل المبسط.
And now we're going to take the simpler form and take its derivative.
والآن سنقوم بأخذ هذا الشكل المبسط، ونستخرج مشتقته.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]